{"id":"2017_11","name":"Romans2017_11","memoryVerse":"“In the same way, count yourselves dead to sin but alive to God in Christ Jesus.” – Romans 6:11 ","dayQuestions":{"one":{"title":"FIRST DAY: Read the notes and the references.","questions":[{"id":"2017_11_1","questionText":"1. What was meaningful to you in the lecture?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_11_2","questionText":"2. What help did you receive from the notes?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"two":{"title":"SECOND DAY: Read Romans 6:12-14.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"6:12-14"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_11_3","questionText":"3. What truths in earlier chapters of Romans precede the word “therefore” in verse 12? (See previous lessons.)  ","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_11_4a","questionText":"4. a. List the two negative commands and the two positive commands, and explain why lasting change requires both negative and positive actions. (See also Ephesians 4:22-24; Colossians 3:9-10.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Ephesians","verse":"4:22-24"},{"book":"Colossians","verse":"3:9-10"}]},{"id":"2017_11_4b","questionText":"4. b.  Give specific ways you are tempted to offer any part of yourself to sin and ways to offer every part of yourself to God.","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_11_5","questionText":"5. How does God’s promise in verse 14 encourage you in light of the commands in verses 12-13? (See also Romans 5:20-21.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"5:20-21"}]}]},"three":{"title":"THIRD DAY: Read Romans 6:15-16.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"6:15-16"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_11_6","questionText":"6. How do the questions in verses 1 and 15 differ, and how are they alike?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_11_7a","questionText":"7. a. What does it mean to “be a slave to sin” or a “slave to righteousness”?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_11_7b","questionText":"7. b. Because we are slaves to the one we obey, would you describe yourself now as a slave to sin or a slave to righteousness, and why?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"four":{"title":"FOURTH DAY: Read Romans 6:17-18.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"6:17-18"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_11_8","questionText":"8. Compare and contrast obedience from the heart and following rules. Which describes your actions?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_11_9","questionText":"9. What is “the pattern of teaching” Paul says “claims the allegiance” of believers? (See Romans 6:1-14 or other Scripture passages.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"6:1-14"}]},{"id":"2017_11_10","questionText":"10. If Christ has set you free from sin, what are some aspects of your freedom for which you thank God? ","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"five":{"title":"FIFTH DAY: Read Romans 6:19-23.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"6:19-23"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_11_11","questionText":"11. List ways in which people want to be free and why these things are or are not true freedom.","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_11_12","questionText":"12. What are the results of being a slave to sin, and what are the results of being a slave to God? ","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_11_13a","questionText":"13. a. How have you personally experienced sin’s wages, which lead to death? If you are a believer, how has God used those things for His glory and your good?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_11_13b","questionText":"13. b. What attitudes and behaviors are produced in you as you meditate on God’s gift of eternal life?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"six":{"title":"SIXTH DAY: Review Romans 6:12-23.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"6:12-23"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_11_14","questionText":"14. What have you learned about God in this week’s study? How may your group pray for you as you make this truth a part of your life?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_11_15","questionText":"15. Homiletics for group and administrative leaders: Romans 6:12-23","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"6:12-23"}]}]}}}